Can you imagine living in a city without roads on the surface?
你能想象生活在一个没有地面道路的城市吗？
We've already put trains underground successfully, but the idea of building roads underground is now inspiring urban planners and engineers.
我们已经成功地将火车置于地下，但建造地下道路的想法现在正激励着城市规划者和工程师。
Bradley Garrett, author of 'Subterranean London', says that there's something magical about things happening out of sight, that it "gives the illusion of seamlessness".
《地下伦敦》一书的作者布拉德利·加勒特说，发生在视线之外的事情有一种魔力，它"给人一种无缝的错觉"。
So, how might underground roads reshape our cities and redefine the daily commute?
那么，地下道路将如何重塑我们的城市并重新定义日常通勤呢？
"If you want to revitalise the city centre, you pedestrianise the roads," says Tom Ireland, the director of tunnelling at engineering company Aurecon.
"如果你想振兴市中心，就把道路改为步行区，"工程公司Aurecon的隧道工程总监汤姆·爱尔兰说。
Moving roads below the surface can free up space for parks, pavement cafes, and other public amenities, improving the urban environment and mental health of the population.
将道路移至地下可以为公园、露天咖啡馆和其他公共设施腾出空间，改善城市环境和人们的心理健康。
Not only that, it could reduce traffic congestion above ground, and who doesn't want to be freed from noise pollution and the sight of gridlocked traffic?
不仅如此，这还能减少地面上的交通拥堵，谁不想摆脱噪声污染和交通堵塞的景象呢？
Underground roads could also make self-driving cars more popular, which are often more energy-efficient, and less prone to collisions.
地下道路也可能使自动驾驶汽车更受欢迎，这类汽车通常更节能，且更不易发生碰撞。
This, in a world trying to reduce its fuel consumption, is appealing.
在一个努力减少燃料消耗的世界里，这一点很有吸引力。
But if driverless cars end up becoming more attractive than public transport, it could actually make traffic worse, because cars take up more space than trains and buses.
但如果无人驾驶汽车最终变得比公共交通更具吸引力，实际上可能会让交通状况更糟，因为汽车比火车和公交车占用更多空间。
That's not the only drawback that may come with a motorised world beneath our feet.
这并不是我们脚下的机动化世界可能带来的唯一缺点。
The construction and maintenance of underground infrastructure are both hazardous and energy-intensive processes.
地下基础设施的建设和维护都是危险且高能耗的过程。
On top of that, most people don't like the feeling of confinement you get when you're travelling through underground tunnels, which may affect public perception.
除此之外，大多数人不喜欢在通过地下隧道旅行时产生的封闭感，这可能会影响公众对地下道路的认知。
Dreams of roadless, car-free cities bring both excitement and scepticism.
无道路、无汽车城市的梦想既令人兴奋和又令人怀疑。
We may fantasise about cityscapes made for pedestrians, but perhaps getting more people to use public transport rather than private vehicles would be more worth our time and resources.
我们可能幻想为行人设计的城市景观，但也许让更多人使用公共交通而不是私家车，更值得我们投入时间和资源。